Some men are too noble to live among aristocracy.
Vatel is a history, drama, romance film directed by Roland Joffé.
In 1671, with war brewing with Holland, a penniless prince invites Louis
XIV to three days of festivities at a chateau in Chantilly.
The prince wants a commission as a general, so the
extravagances are to impress the king.
In charge of all is the steward, Vatel, a man of honor, talent, and low birth.
The prince is craven in his longing for stature: no task is too
menial or dishonorable for him to give Vatel.
While Vatel tries to sustain dignity, he finds himself attracted
to Anne de Montausier, the king's newest mistress.
In Vatel, she finds someone who's authentic, living out his
principles within the casual cruelties of court politics.
Can the two of them escape unscathed?
Francois Vatel, played by Gérard Depardieu.
Anne de Montausier, played by Uma Thurman.
Marquis de Lauzun, played by Tim Roth.
Gourville, played by Timothy Spall.
Prince de Conde, played by Julian Glover.
Louis XIV, played by Julian Sands.
Vatel is a 2000 historical drama film directed by Roland Joffé, written by Jeanne Labrune and translated by Tom
Stoppard, and starring Gérard Depardieu, Uma Thurman, Tim Roth, Timothy Spall, Julian Glover and Julian Sands.
The film, based on the life of 17th-century French chef François Vatel,
was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Art Direction.
The film opened the 2000 Cannes Film Festival.
The film explores themes of france, prince, chef, 17th century, louis xiv.
The tone is emotional.